vkhosa@asu.edu (669) 499-6484 www.linkedin.com/in/vasundrakhosa

SUMMARY

Self-driven and experienced business analytics major with an educational background in data science, visualization and descriptive and predictive analytics applications. I am passionate to apply Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning to solve real-world problems. A professional with strong background of leading business analytics projects in diverse domains of software, marketing and operations.

EDUCATION

W. P. Carey School of Business at Arizona State University

August 2022 – May 2023

Master of Science in Business Analytics | GPA: 4.0/4.0 (with Distinction)

Tempe, AZ

Relevant Coursework: AI & ML Applications, Data Mining, Deep Learning, Descriptive & Predictive Statistics, Business Process Analytics, Database Management Systems, Analytical Decision Making & Optimization Tools, Deep Learning, Digital Marketing

Warwick Business School, University of Warwick

October 2018 – September 2019

Master of Science in Management of Information Systems and Digital Innovation | CGPA: 67/100 (with Merit)

Coventry, UK

Relevant Coursework: Digital Business Strategy, Business Intelligence, SAP, Cybersecurity, Project Management

Nirma University July 2013 – June 2017 Ahmedabad, India

Bachelor of Technology Computer Engineering | CGPA: 7.2/10 (First Class with Merit)

(3 years 5 months)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cintas Corporation, Business Analytics Intern

January 2023 - May 2023

- Led a team working on developing strategic business insights that enabled executive management to gain actionable insights into their demand fulfillment process across over 1000 products. Highlighted product demand trends and seasonality through 4 interactive and user-friendly Tableau dashboards on SAP data.
- Built a predictive model to forecast product sales at multiple distribution centers for various material groups employing advanced forecasting techniques such as statistical method (SARIMA), exponential smoothening and machine learning algorithms implemented in Python, highlighted opportunities to reduce excess safety stock by 50% resulting in \$15.1M savings.

Bennett Coleman and Co. Ltd. (The Times Group), Deputy Manager – Business Analyst

January 2022 – August 2022

- Managed a team responsible for designing and innovating asset governance policies and standard operating procedures to ensure complete software and hardware compliance across the organization using GRC module of SAP to track software allocation requests leading to 100% compliance across all group companies.
- Defined KPI's and created business relevant PowerBI dashboards and detailed excel trackers for internal stakeholders to visualize utilization of hardware assets to review and analyze optimization of software utilization resulting in savings of \$7.7M.

Karcher Cleaning Systems Pvt. Ltd., Marketing Analyst

December 2019 – December 2021

- Managed search and display campaigns on Amazon and Flipkart with the budget of \$8M leading to increase in sales by \$80M by implementing customer segmentation and re-targeting based on demographics.
- Evaluated metrics effecting website traffic, curated SEO content for content management system (Typo3) by deploying tools like Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics, Google Search Console and communicated insights to leadership.
- Initiated collaboration with cross-functional teams and negotiation with vendors to ensure compliance for branding 14 channel-partner shops PAN India and procurement of marketing collaterals worth \$1M.

Continuum ElectroProducts LLP, Business Analyst

July 2017 - March 2018

- Developed SQL database and programmed complex SQL queries to extract, transform, load, and analyze the data to explore the current product stock status resulting in a decline of 10% inventory costs.
- Worked in **agile environment** and used Jira dashboard for project management tasks monitoring project progress.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- Solar Energy Analysis- Built predictive models using Monte Carlo simulation to analyze relationship between energy demand, solar-panel generation and temporal changes in the energy costs predicting the savings of a household by using solar panels.
- Career Center Survey Process- Developed a Tableau dashboard highlighting insights about gap in survey drop rate and implemented Lean Six Sigma DMAIC strategy resulting in an increase of 25% response rate of ASU career center survey process.
- Visualization of Medical Records Created a Tableau dashboard utilizing SQL data extraction and transformation to visualize clinical data including electronic health records, facilitating data-driven decision making for critical clinical scenarios.
- Image Classification Optimized a Convolution Neural Network(CNN) model for CIFAR-10 image recognition using **Keras** library with InceptionV3 and DenseNet models and preprocessed images using **NumPy** array achieving 85% accuracy.

SKILLS & ACTIVITIES

- Computer Skills: SAP, MySQL, Python, Tableau, C#, .NET, Microsoft Excel, Minitab, QlikSense, PowerBI, HTML, PowerPoint
- Technical Skills: Data Visualization, Business Intelligence, Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Natural Language Processing, Design Thinking by IBM, SPSS, Data Modeling, Insight generation, Lean Six Sigma Green Belt certification, Regression, Data Warehouse
- **Interests:** A sustainability enthusiast with a passion to explore Europe and savor its diverse chocolates.